The Princess Sapphire
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Princess Knight,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Twenty-Fifth Episode
The King's Ghost
Before telling you
the story of today,
we will briefly remind you of
the previous episodes.
The King disappeared
and it was decided that Sapphire
...would be crowned King.
But on the day of the ceremony,
the Queen,
drugged by Duralumin and Nylon,
revealed that Sapphire was a girl.
So the Queen and Sapphire were
locked in the Coffin Tower.
Duralumin began
to tyrannize the people.
Learning this, Sapphire escaped through a
hole shown to her by a little mouse...
...e, in the guise of the phantom
knight, freed the prisoners.
Duralumin, suspecting
che il cavaliere fantasma...
...could be Sapphire,
sent assassins to the tower.
But Sapphire, warned by the little mouse,
managed to capture them...
.and send them back to Duralumin
After freeing some children,
taken prisoner
to lure him into a trap,
Sapphire, in the guise
of the phantom knight,
manages to enter the castle
and steal the royal crown.
Infuriated, Duralumin decides
to entrust Gama, the jailer,
with the task of killing
the Queen and Sapphire.
And now Gama prepares himself
for his sad task.
Will he succeed?
Help! Help!
Thank you, dear little mice!
You saved my life!
What's happening, Sapphire?
Mother, Gama has fainted.
My God! We must do something
Here.
But... what the hell did he do to you?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?!
What do you mean "nothing"?!
He wanted to make an attempt on your life!
- He has a knife.
- What?
Well, I'm sure he was
surprised by the rats...
...and tried to chase them
away with the knife, but he fell.
Let's do something,
otherwise he will die!
Now he really seems
to be doing better.
Let's boil a little
more water!
I'll give you a hand!
Shut up, idiot!
Try again
and this time without an escort.
You must succeed in
killing her absolutely!
I will kill those who follow her.
- Here you go, mother.
- Thank you, dear.
There was a scoundrel!
Yes...
Gama, you saved me!
Yes, I saved you.
Gama, thank you! Thank you!
Thank you so much!
Thank you so much, Gama!
You're welcome! You're welcome!
There!
Listen, Gama,
mice are cute, aren't they?
Yes, that's true!
They really are very cute!
Thank you for your
delicious dinner, Gama!
And now I must go!
The Phantom Knight!
I will no longer try
to tyrannize Sapphire!
It's true, I have become a staunch
defender of Princess Sapphire
..and also of the Queen!
- Now I understand!
- That's right!
The enemies of the Phantom Knight
are Duralumin and Nylon.
To defeat Duralumin,
I will go... even into the castle!
But how restless
this girl is!
Speaking of the castle,
do you know about that noise?
- What noise? - Every night,
a strange noise is heard...
..in the stone well.
They say it's the ghost of the King
wandering around the castle!
- My father's ghost?!
- My God!
Yes, but Duralumin
has anyone put in prison..
...whoever says they have seen
the ghost, or talks about him.
Then I'm going to the stone
well, so I'll know something too.
This must be the
entrance to the stone well.
The guard seems
rather thorough.
Open up!
This is the moment!
Close it!
The ghost knight!
Close it, quick! Close it!
Excuse me, but I'm going through anyway!
Damn, it's breaking!
Damn you!
Work harder! Work, quickly!
Come on, push!
Help me push!
Water! Water!
I want to drink!
I'm so thirsty!
If the Ghost Knight
appeared at the stone well...
- Ah, Ghost Knight!
- Don't joke around!
The Ghost Knight
doesn't really exist!
It's a children's dream!
If it goes on like this,
we will die of thirst!
Water?! No, it's impossible!
Reality is something else!
Then this must
surely be an illusion!
Who poured
water on my face?
There's water?!
- Water! Water!
- Water!
This really is water!
How dare you
take some water?
Ehi, you!
Don't tyrannize the weak!
But this is the voice
of the Ghost Knight!
Where are you? Show yourself!
Where are you?
The Ghost Knight!
Get him! Quick!
Grab him!
Come on, let's get him!
Hup!
- Please, don't hurt us!
- All right! Take the chains off everyone!
Yes, sir!
Uranaru! Garigori! Balia!
But how does he know our names?
Be quiet!
Prince!... Oh, no! King Sapphire!
I'm so happy...
...that you are safe!
- I have to take care of something
I want to know about the ghost
of my father.
I know the details,
because everyone...
...who, in some way,
has heard of him...
..has been brought here
Someone heard his footsteps.
- Has no one seen him?
- No, no one.
It is said that every night,
at midnight,
the voice
and the footsteps of the King...
..are heard coming from the dungeons.
From the dungeons?
It must be almost midnight.
I'm getting the shivers!
- Hey, it'll start in a bit!
- Shut up!
"The third stone
under the lion decoration".
One, two, three...
This is it!
But this is a huge crypt!
It's midnight.
My father's voice!
There he is!
Father!
- My father!
- Who's there?
Father, you are alive! Father!
But you are Sapphire!
- My father!
- You're alive too.
- Father, mother is doing well too!
- Really?
But how did you end up here?
Who the hell confined you
to this place?
I don't know.
I couldn't see them.
That night,
that is, when I was kidnapped,
I was in my room and I was
writing an important proclamation..
...when they kidnapped me
and brought me to these dungeons,
where I was locked up
without enough food and water.
The enemy wanted you to
die of hunger. That's it, isn't it?
- Yes. There is something more important.
- What?
I would really
like us to find...
...that proclamation I
was writing that night.
- It was burned, wasn't it?
- Yes.
But I wrote it on leather, so
it must have remained intact.
Sapphire, could you find it?
The phantom knight!
What? The phantom knight?
You are still sleeping... The
guard is too vigilant and alert...
...to allow him
to enter. Stupid!
Here it is! I found it!
It ended up in a strange place
It's too dark to read it
- Hey!
- I'm sorry, sir.
- Give me the torch!
- Yes, sir!
"King's Proclamation".
Now I can read it!
Thank you very much!
You're welcome, sir.
Damn!
Well, look at that...
Read this!
This proclamation has been posted
on all the city walls!
"Today, at ten, everyone gather
in front of the castle gate!
- The Phantom Knight".
- What should we do? Shall we go?
Of course! Maybe we'll get to see
something interesting.
Drive them away!
Use arrows, cannons
whatever you want, but drive them away!
But there are too many of them
to drive them away!
Damn him! What does he want to do?
Attention!
I want you all to see a man!
Duralumin! Nylon!
Look at him closely!
But it's the Queen! How did she escape
from the coffin tower?!
The King! It's impossible!
How wonderful!
Long live the King!
- Hooray! Hooray!
- Long live the King!
I was confined
in the dungeons...
...and I was about to be killed.
I'm sorry, but I don't know who
the criminal who wanted to kill me is.
Thanks to the phantom knight,
I was saved and did not die!
- Hooray for the phantom knight!
- Hooray!
Now, father, let's go to the castle!
I will not let you enter!
You are no longer the King!
- Now Plastic is the King!
- Shut up, Duralumin!
This castle belongs to me
and to my heir Sapphire!
Heir?!
No, she is not the heir!
According to our law, a woman
cannot succeed to the throne!
This was true
until I modified the law!
Modified the law?!
Can you show any proof?
The proof is here!
This is the authentic law,
bearing the King's seal!
Before being imprisoned,
I wrote and sealed it!
Damn it!
And now I will announce before
all the people my proclamation!
"This I declare as King:
I modify the original law,
which established that a woman...
..could not succeed
to the throne of Silverland.
Now a woman can be Queen
and rule the country"!
Mother!
Listen, dad... so I
am no longer King, now...
No, you're not! You bore!
But is it really true?
I'm no longer King?
Shut up, idiot!
Good! Good!
How wonderful! Oh, how wonderful!
And now let's go to the castle!
- Hooray!
- Great!
Damn it! Do you think
I will resign myself and surrender?
Princess! Princess Sapphire!
It's strange that you wear
boy's clothes.
It's true. Thank you, maiden
Thank you so much! But I still want to
wear boy's clothes.
I will do so until in this country
there are no more tyrants.
But I promise you that, when
peace finally arrives,
this dress will be
the first one I'll wear!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP